# Jamie McCarthy

# Workplace Experience Lead

#### **Jamie McCarthy**

Tallaght Dublin, D24YE36

0851851846 mccarthyjamie506@gmail.com

#### Skills

I am a self motivated worker and always work to learn new skills in order to better achieve both my own and my team's goals. I work well in fast paced environments and enjoy adapting to new workflows.

During my previous roles I have gained a number of skills, including excellent verbal and written communication skills. I also have extensive experience in both Google Suite and Microsoft Office.

#### **Experience**

#### Jones Lang LaSalle @ Amazon Ireland / Workplace Experience Lead

November 2022 - PRESENT, Dublin

- Built upon existing reporting tools used to calculate meeting room metrics and improved overall performance, reducing time taken for the task from 20+ minutes to 1 minute using Excel VBA Macros and Outlook.
- Developed and Launched an internal tool to aid in the navigation of and access to a regional Shared Drive, comprising 4 sites currently with the possibility to extend. This was done using self taught skills in HTML, Python, CSS and Java.
- Took ownership of contractor logs and sign-in forms from within the reception shortly after joining the company, ensuring that logs were kept up to date and orderly as well as keeping in line with data retention policies.
- Helped lead Return to Office Initiatives alongside FM and AFM, including creating
  and posting new signage across a number of sites, updating employee
  workstations to keep in line with new corporate scope and providing site
  introductions to new and returning staff.
- Took ownership of annual leave tracking for the Dublin team, updating the
  primary tracking sheet to provide clear metrics on leave taken and a system to
  avoid any accidental leave crossover between key personnel.
- Assisted in the planning and organization of several large scale events, including working closely with clients, onsite security teams and onsite catering team to ensure smooth and high quality running of the events.

#### Center for Talented Youth Ireland/ Instructor

May 2022 - November 2022, Dublin

- Delivered easily understandable and highly interactive courses of Third Level course contact to Second Level Students, leading to high levels of understanding and project output.
- Managed a number of Teaching Assistants in each course, ensuring that they were able to adequately work with the class and provide further assistance to those pupils who required it.
- Took on roles teaching outside my usual subject matter area of Game Design,

- working to educate myself on these topics to a high level in order to deliver an in-depth and engaging course to both Secondary and Primary Level students.
- Hired for a single course semester but was kept on staff for a number of extra courses due to positive feedback from parents.

## **Dublin City Council - Markievicz & Irishtown Leisure Centers /** Relief Attendant

July 2017 - November 2022, Dublin

- Worked closely with Center Management as the Reception Lead, creating training documents and delivering training to incoming staff on reception routines and operations.
- Promoted to Swimming Coordinator in order to take ownership of both Adults and Childrens Swimming Lessons, conducting a restructure of their operation before launching them. This relaunch gained roughly 100 new participants versus the previous courses, serving as a 65% increase versus previous attendance levels.
- Asked to serve as additional Manager of the Irishtown Leisure Centre, including reorganizing and updating the member onboarding procedures to align with other Dublin City Council Facilities.
- Served as primary staff contact on site for a number of large scale events in both Markievicz and Irishtown Leisure Centres.
- Organized Dublin City Council Sports & Recreation Pride event for 2021, having assisted in planning for several previous years, hosted between Markievicz and Irishtown. This involved planning, procurement, fundraising and advertising.

#### **Education**

#### **TU Dublin / BA Games Design**

September 2017 - August 2021, Dublin

- Received a Second Class Honors, First Degree in Games Design (Level 8).
- Served as Production Lead on a number of projects throughout the course, including when working with external stakeholders in order to produce high quality projects with multi-disciplinary teams.
- Developed a strong understanding of SCRUM, Agile and Waterfall production and project management techniques.
- A project I lead placed in the top 10 of the Unity Game Based Learning Competition in 2019 and was selected to present at the Irish Game Based Learning Conference the same year.

### Volunteer & Leadership Experience

- Volunteered with the St.John's Ambulance for 10 years, including teaching first aid and working at community events
- HEAR Mentor in University for incoming First Year Students
- While in University I sat on the committee of a number of Societie.
- Held a seat on the DIT/TU Dublin Students Union and acted as School Rep for the then DIT School of Media.
- Outside of university and work I help run an LGBTQ focused game night in Dublin called the "Dublin Gaymers" and have helped raise several thousand euro for various charities through this group's charity events.